Hello, my friends, and welcome to exercise number 79.
And this exercise, we are asked to implement the queue in Java, but in Link using Link, at least
we have seen in the previous video how to implement the queue in Java using arrays.
Now we are going to implement the queue using the link.
At least we click on the resource folder.
We click on Java class and I will create a queue link link.
At least El-Al.
OK?
Que al.
This refers for creating a queue using clean kit less.
OK, now and this.
Class A will create a subclass called Cunard.
OK.
Similar to the linked list, but and we are using the basics of using Link Atlas to make this.
Q que no.
This is the reference to it.
And next, this we have seen in the linked list constructor for that public.
Q no to.
Q A. It took him to perimeter in key and this dirt key equal to key.
And this dirt next equal to no.
Okay.
Because the next of this would be referring to the no no A-Class to represent a Q.
This is the class that we are going to create for the Q.
Here we go.
The Q and L.
Okay, so.
The actual URL contains the known.
And now we make, you know, both front and rear.
The queue here, the front store is the front node of link at least, and the last note of AL is stored
in the rear.
OK, so we will create a constructor public
public.
Q l l.
Here.
And we start by initializing the front equal to this three year equal to not
gay, no methods to add a key to their cue.
We need that in cue and in order to remove the kids, we need to their method.
OK, so here we start by making void in in que exactly that.
We have seen this in the previous video, but in the different concept now using the link ad lists.
So if you create a new node in your linkage list, no.
So you node them.
Stamp equal to a new Q Note that.
Thank you.
And if this the three equal equal to none, then we check if the queue is empty, then the new node
is.
This front equal to this, though, to be here equal term, then return.
OK, now adding then you know, at the end of the queue, this rear door next equal to them.
And this the three years equal to 10.
OK, this is how we in queue announced.
Let's make a method that removes the element or remove a key from queue.
So the void deck.
It's void and no arguments.
Check if that is a queue is empty, then return, not if this don't prompt equal equal to no, then
return.
Now storing the previous front and move front one.
But one element?
OK, move front.
One item forward one note that OK, so queue A. Stamp
equals this third front.
And this third front equal to this third round the next.
Now check if the front becomes null, then change that here.
Also, as not here would check if this dot from equal, equal to null, then change.
Also, three of this three is equal to none.
The trick behind using that link, at least, is to make the two notes the front and rear and try to
play with them, according that if you are removing or if you are adding date now let's create a driver
class public static void main.
I have a string of ARGs
and
Q Q equal to you, Q, and let's start in cuing in Q then and Q I will create a Q was like that Q that
in Q to any.
Q, without being Q 30, Q the Q 40, now let's start
printing them.
So Q dot display.
It's run and see this would click on run to cure them and l'Allemagne.
And here we go.
We have inserted 10, 20, 30 and 40.
The front end is zero.
The items 10 to 10, 20, 30 and 40.
OK.
And here we go, we have done.
I think everything here is very simple.
We have Q and Q thank.
Oops!
I have created Queue.
I need Alal.
OK.
I am.
I'm seeing here that we didn't need any parameters and we didn't create the display.
So you see, guys, we have made this mistake.
So this play here, so I need to just bring that forward and there the queue front and the acuity.
So system to out the print goes, we didn't create a display.
It's the same as the previous.
So you can't copy it from the cube.
So cue from is equal to pure dot feront dot key.
We need it's key.
Okay.
And if I need the cube research, then I will use every year here and we start.
So we are printing the key, the front key and the key.
We have inserted 10, 20, 30 and 40.
Then is the beginning the front and that here is 40.
And you can go through all of these nodes exactly as the same as the Lincoln list.
So congratulations, guys, we have implemented that you using the arrays.
And in this video, we have implemented the Q using link at.